Should you recycle the box from your takeaway pizza or throw it away?
你应该把外卖披萨的盒子回收利用还是扔掉呢？
Can you recycle aerosol cans?
你能回收喷雾罐吗？
Is all plastic recyclable?
所有的塑料都可以回收吗？
How clued up about recycling are you?
你对回收利用了解多少呢？
We probably all know that recycling is good for the environment.
我们可能都知道回收利用对环境有好处。
It saves energy and limits the drain on Earth's resources.
它能节约能源，减少对地球资源的消耗。
But do you know which items you should or shouldn't recycle?
但是你知道哪些东西应该回收，哪些不应该回收吗？
In the UK, we have a well-established system of kerbside recycling.
在英国，我们有一套完善的路边回收系统。
Most people expect to separate recyclable material from general refuse.
大多数人希望将可回收材料与一般垃圾分开。
A typical household recycles paper, cardboard, plastic and glass bottles, foil and drinks cans.
一个典型的家庭会回收纸张、硬纸板、塑料和玻璃瓶、箔纸以及饮料罐。
Food and garden waste is now also collected.
现在也会收集食物和花园垃圾。
But in the last four years, the number of items rejected for recycling in England has gone up by 84%, mainly as a result of contamination.
但在过去四年里，英格兰被拒绝回收物品数量增加了84%，主要是由于污染造成的。
Many items end up in landfill or being incinerated when, with more care, they could be recycled.
许多物品最终被填埋在垃圾填埋场或被焚烧，而如果更加小心处理的话，它们是可以被回收利用的。
The problem often stems from confusion over what and how to recycle.
这个问题往往源于对回收什么以及如何回收的困惑。
Across the UK the system of recycling differs between local authorities, and multiple containers are used for different types of recyclables.
在英国各地，地方当局的回收系统各不相同，并且会使用多个容器来装不同类型的可回收物品。
In one area there may be one large wheelie bin for recycling all household items, another for garden waste, and yet another for general waste.
在一个地区，可能会有一个大的有轮大垃圾桶来回收所有的家庭物品，另一个用来装花园垃圾，还有一个用来装一般垃圾。
There are also composting food caddies - a small one for the kitchen and a larger one for the kerbside.
也有用于堆肥的食物小桶——厨房用的小一点，路边用的大一点。
These use compostable bags for food waste, including tea bags, coffee grindings and egg shells.
这些会使用可降解的袋子来装食物垃圾，包括茶包、咖啡渣和蛋壳。
A few streets away, another council may use a separate container just for glass bottles.
在几条街之外，另一个市政当局可能会使用一个单独的容器专门用来装玻璃瓶。
Waste collection times vary - either weekly or fortnightly.
垃圾收集时间各不相同——有的是每周一次，有的是每两周一次。
Each week, you have to remember which bin has to go out.
每周，你都得记住该把哪个垃圾桶拿出去。
It's all highly confusing.
这一切都非常令人困惑。
One of the biggest problems recycling firms face is food contamination.
回收公司面临的最大问题之一是食物污染。
If your plastic milk bottle is empty, it's ok to recycle it, but if it contains a small amount of milk, it could result in contamination of the plastic recycling process.
如果你的塑料牛奶瓶是空的，那么可以回收它，但如果里面还有少量牛奶，就可能会导致塑料回收过程受到污染。
Likewise, paper fibres cannot be recycled if they are contaminated with food, so a cheesy pizza box shouldn't be recycled.
同样地，如果纸纤维被食物污染了就无法回收，所以一个有奶酪的披萨盒不应该被回收。
Conscientious consumers are constantly faced with recycling conundrums.
有良知的消费者经常会面临回收方面的难题。
You've just finished a carton of juice.
你刚喝完一盒果汁。
Should you remove the plastic cap before recycling the carton?
在回收纸盒之前，你应该把塑料盖子拿掉吗？
You feel the fate of the planet lies in your hands.
你觉得地球的命运掌握在你的手中。
My advice: stop worrying and crack open a bottle of beer! ...Hang on! ... what should you do with the bottle top?!
我的建议是：别再担心了，打开一瓶啤酒吧！……等等！……那你该怎么处理瓶盖呢？！